A Guide to the Papers of Charles Wright ca. 1890-1998
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Charles Wright ca. 1890-1998
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
11437
38 Hollinger boxes, ca. 16 linear shelf feet
This collection consists of the papers of American poet and University of Virginia English professor, Charles Penzel Wright (1935 - ), ca. 5,000 items (38 Hollinger boxes, ca. 16 linear shelf feet), ca. 1890-1999, including manuscripts, poetry and translation notebooks kept by Charles Wright, professional and personal correspondence, photographs, printed material, news clippings, artwork, interviews, book reviews, and tape recordings.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The collection is without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was acquired by the University of Virginia Library from Charles Wright, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia, on October 5, 1998, and is unrestricted.
Biographical/Historical Information
Charles Wright was born in Pickwick Dam, Hardin County, Tennessee on August 25, 1935, to Charles Penzel and Mary Castleman (Winter) Wright, and was educated at Davidson College (B.A., 1957), the University of Iowa Writer's Workshop (M.F.A., 1963) and the University of Rome (1963-1964). He served in the United States Army Intelligence Corps, 1957-1961, where he studied at the Army Language School, Monterey, California, the first year. He spent the remaining three years of service in and around Verona, Italy, returning there to study on a Fulbright grant in 1963-1964.
Since 1966, Wright has been an English professor, first at the University of California, Irvine (1966-1983), and then at the University of Virginia (1983 until the present). He married Holly McIntire in 1969, and published his first book of poems, The Grave of the Right Hand, in 1970. Other titles of poetry include: Hard Freight(1973); Bloodlines(1975); China Trace(1977); The Southern Cross(1981); Country Music: Selected Early Poems(1982); The Other Side of the River(1984); Zone Journals(1988); The World of Ten Thousand Things: Poems 1980-1990(1990); Chickamauga(1995); Black Zodiac(1997) and Appalachia(1998). During his entire career, Wright has won national recognition for his poetry. Several of these awards include the Edgar Allan Poe Award from the Academy of American Poets for Bloodlines(1976), the National Book Award in poetry for Country Music: Selected Early Poems(1983), the Ruth Lilly Poetry prize (1993), the Academy of American Poets Lenore Marshall Poetry Prize for Chickamauga(1996), and the Pulitzer Prize for Poetry for Black Zodiac(1998). He has also received awards for his work in translation, notably the PEN Translation Prize for his translation of the Italian poet Eugenio Montale's The Storm and Other Things. Wright has also published translations of the Italian poet Dino Campana ( Orphic Songs, 1984).
For more complete biographical and professional information consult the Gale Literary Database on Contemporary Authors and the web site for the Pulitzer Prizes on the Internet, Wright's essay in The Contemporary Authors Autobiography Series, the essay about Wright by George F. Buttrick in The Dictionary of Literary Biography, the volume The Point Where All Things Meet: Essays on Charles Wright collected and edited by Tom Andrews, and the biographical folder in Box 36. Also helpful are the two collections of critical essays and interviews about Wright published in Halflife: Improvisations and Interviews, 1977-1987, University of Michigan Press (1988) and Quarter Notes: Improvisations and Interviews, University of Michigan Press (1995).
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of the papers of American poet and University of Virginia English professor, Charles Penzel Wright (1935 - ), ca. 5,000 items (38 Hollinger boxes, ca. 16 linear shelf feet), ca. 1890- 1999, including manuscripts, poetry and translation notebooks kept by Charles Wright, professional and personal correspondence, photographs, printed material, news clippings, artwork, interviews, book reviews, and tape recordings.
The correspondence files with other poets and literary persons and family, have been arranged by the last name of the correspondent (Boxes 1-17). The more frequent correspondents and correspondence with some of the other Pulitzer Prize winners in poetry have been placed in separate folders with the total number of letters noted in the guide.
Correspondence with persons who have been awarded the Pulitzer Prize for Poetry include: John Ashbery (1 item), Louise Gluck (6 items), Jorie Graham (13 items), Anthony Hecht (1 item), Richard Howard (4 items), Donald Justice (142 items), Galway Kinnell (3 items), Yusef Komunyakaa (1 item), Maxine Kumin (1 item), Philip Levine (207 items), William Meredith (3 items), W.S. Merwin (11 items), Lisel Mueller (1 item), Charles Simic (31 items), James Tate (27 items), Robert Penn Warren (2 items), and Richard Wilbur (2 items).
Other types of correspondence are arranged chronologically in a separate subseries B (Boxes 17-21). This includes correspondence about awards, conferences, workshops, poetry readings and other professional engagements, poems submitted to or accepted by poetry magazines and anthologies, and requests for Wright to judge poetry contests, write recommendations or evaluate candidates for academic positions; greeting cards; post cards; and invitations and announcements.
Of special interest in series two containing manuscripts by Charles Wright are the twelve volumes of hand-written poetry kept by Wright in bound notebooks, from 1968 until the present. These contain his autograph poems in chronological order as they were written. When the poems were used in his published books, Wright would mark through them in pencil. The manuscript series also has an autograph volume for Wright's translation work and one called "Halflife ( A Commonplace Notebook)," where he has recorded quotes or his own thoughts about poetry and related subjects.
Also present in a second subseries and arranged according to the title of the book, are typescripts, setting copies, page proofs, and galleys, for many of his published works, although some typescripts of early manuscripts had already been sold to private collectors in the early eighties prior to the acquisition of these papers by the Library.
A third subseries contains copies of miscellaneous manuscripts by Charles Wright, including: a copy of his Masters Thesis submitted at the University of Iowa, typescripts and galleys of individual poems published in magazines such as The New Yorker, and miscellaneous other manuscripts by Wright.
A third series contains manuscripts by other authors sent to Wright for his comment or enjoyment and are arranged by the last name of the author. Most are not complete manuscripts of books by other authors, but when they are and the title of the book is known, it is included in the guide. Some are accompanied by letters from the authors, often discussing their work.
Series four contains miscellaneous papers including: interviews and essays about Charles Wright, artwork by other people, biographical entries about Wright, contracts and publication agreements, a dissertation chapter about Wright, news clippings and printed, photographs, programs, reviews of books by Wright, royalties and honorariums, student papers about Wright, translations of Wright's poetry into Italian and German, interviews and poetry readings by Wright on audio tape, and oversize photographs, artwork, news clippings, dust jackets, and a Winter family genealogical chart.
Organization
This collection has been arranged in the following series and subseries:
Series I: Correspondence:
Subseries A: Alphabetical Correspondence arranged by last name of correspondent (Boxes 1-17)
Subseries B: Chronological Correspondence arranged by date (Boxes 17-21)
Series II: Manuscripts of Works by Charles Wright
Subseries A: Bound Volumes of Poetry & Translation Notebooks kept by Charles Wright (Boxes 21-23)
Subseries B: Poetry Manuscripts Arranged by Title of Book (Boxes 24-29)
Subseries C: Miscellaneous Manuscripts (Box 29)
Series III: Manuscripts by Other Authors arranged by the name of the author (Boxes 30-35)
Series IV: Miscellaneous Papers (Boxes 36-38)
Contents List
- Correspondence 1967-1998, n.d. (Box 1-21)
  Arranged alphabetically by last name of correspondent
  - A: Alphabetical Correspondence 1967-1998, n.d. (Box 1-17)
    - A 1984-1997, 19 items (Box 1)
      including: Brian J. Adams, Elizabeth Adams, W. Howard Adams, Dr. Nicoletta Alegi, Allen Anderson, Paul Anderson, Dyerval Angelini, Bim Angst, Philip Appleman, John Ashbery, Jan Austin-Hicken
    - Ai (Florence Anthony, 1947-) 1970-1985, 15 items (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, Debra Allbery (1957-) 1994-1998, 8 items (Box 1)
    - Michael Anania (1939-) 1975-1996, 8 (Box 1)
    - Tom Andrews (1961-) 1984-1994, 35 items (Box 1)
    - Ralph Angel (1951-) 1976-1990, 13 items (Box 1)
    - Ba-Be 1975-1998 (Box 1)
      including: Lea Baechler, Dr. William J. Bailey, David Baker, Rosetta Baker, Samuel M. Baker, Jr., [?] Banks, Katherine A. Barham, Jim Barnes ( The Chariton Review), Virginia Meadors Barrett, Amy Bartlett, Rick Bass, Joan Baum, Bruce Beasley, Vereen M. Bell, Pam Beck, Pinckney Benedict, Donna Bennett, Steve Benson, Kimber Bentley, Steve Berg, David Berman
    - Bi-By 1975-1996 (Box 1)
      including: S. Bishop, Randy Blasing, Laurel Blossom, Joe Bolton, Philip Booth, David Bottoms, Lucius H. Bracey, Jr., Bob Bradley, Dr. Ben B. Braude, Robert Bringhurst, Bunt Britton, Robert Broadway, Anne Brockenbrough, Olga Broumas, David Brown, Sharon Bryan, Heather Burns, S. Burris, Kathryn Stripling Byer
    - Calvin Bedient 1980-1996, 15 items (Box 1)
    - Marvin Bell (1937-), 48 items (2 folders) 1967-1998, 48 items (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Don Bogen 1987-1998, 7 items (Box 2)
    - Ken Botnick 1985-1987, 10 items (Box 2)
    - James Brasfield 1981-1996, 11 items (Box 2)
    - Lucie Brock-Boido 1984-1995, 12 items (Box 2)
    - Christopher Buckley 1980-1997, 22 items (Box 2)
    - Julia Budenz 1989-1996, 6 items (Box 2)
    - Franco Buffoni 1996-1997, 9 items (Box 2)
    - Ca 1984-1997 (Box 2)
      including: Christopher Cahill, Scott Cairns, Paul W. Carmen, Julie Carr, Keith Cartwright, Raymond Carver, Crysta Casey, John Casteen
    - Ch-Cu 1972-1998 (Box 2)
      including: Stacey Chase, Alan Cheuse, Dale Chihuly, Mike Chrisman, Ian Clarke, Karen Clark, Kevin Clark, William Clark, Vince Clemente, Brian Clements, Joshua Clover, Henri Cole, Katie Coles, Michael Collier, Douglas Collins, Floyd Collins, D. Steven Conkle, Jan Conn, Matthew Cooperman, Bonnie Costello, Stephen Coyner, Nancy Crampton, Sybil Crawford, Brad Crenshaw, Cheryl Cross, Pat Cutting
    - Karen Cangialosi 1980-1990, 21 items (Box 2)
    - Paul Carroll (1927-) 1971-1972, 1981, 7 items (Box 2)
    - Michael Chitwood 1990-1997, 7 items (Box 3)
    - Nicholas Christopher 1982-1988, 11 items (Box 3)
    - Killarney Clary 1977-1995, 8 items (Box 3)
    - Jeff Cobb 1983-1984, 1995, 5 items (Box 3)
    - Alfred Corn (1943-) 1976-1987, 9 items (Box 3)
    - Tony Crunk 1994-1997, 4 items (Box 3)
    - Michale Cuddihy 1973-1978, 9 items (Box 3)
    - D 1977-1997 (Box 3)
      including: Mack C. Dagenhart, Robert Dana, David Daniel, Daniel D'Arezzo, Chalmers Davidson, Lisa Davies, William Virgil Davis, Peter Davison, Sara Dawson, S.R. Day, Thomas Day, Phil Deaver, Gene DeGruson, Chip Delffs, Annie Dillard, Fred Dings, Simone DiPiero, Jim Dissette, Lynn Dow, Lynn Doyle, Becky Dunham, Sharon Dunn, Stephen Dunn
    - Jordan Davies 1983-1986, 11 items (Box 3)
    - Wayne Dodd (1930-) 1986-1997, 8 items (Box 3)
    - E 1973-1997 (Box 3)
      including: Carol Ellis, Jon Enfield, John Engels, Hualing Engle, John Erickson, George Estreich, Pete Everwine
    - F 1977-1998 (Box 3)
      including: Robert Fagles, Farrar, Straus & Giroux, Inc., Ruth Feldman, Casey Finch, Reed Finlay, Michael Fitzgerald, Ryan Flaherty, Mary [Flinn?], Harry Ford, Thomas Foster, Linda Jones Foster, Alastair Fowler, Bob Freedman, Terry Freeman, Philip Fried
    - Benson Fenn 1987-1990, 9 items (Box 3)
    - Carolyn Forche 1972-1996, 5 items (Box 3)
    - Richard Ford (1944-) 1974-1978, 5 items (Box 3)
    - Antonella Francini 1985-1997, 9 items (Box 3)
    - David Freed 1979-1997, 11 items (Box 3)
    - Stuart Friebert (1931-) 1983-1988, 18 items (Box 3)
    - Ga 1974-1997 (Box 4)
      including: Gale Research Company re Contemporary Authors, Tess Gallagher, Jim Galvin, Mark Gamble, Forrest Gander, John W. Garden, George Garrett, Joseph M. Garrison, Jr.
    - Ge-Gu 1970-1997 (Box 4)
      including: Alessandro Gentili, Margaret Gibson, Stephen Robert Gibson, Dana Gioia, Steven Clay, Michele Glazer, Greg Glazner, Dave Godfrey, Anne Goodman, Steve Goodwin, Linda Gregerson, Arthur Gregor, Maxine Groffsky, Lollie Groth, Chuck Guilford, Thom Gunn, Carol Gunther
    - Jonathan Galassi 1976-1992, 34 items (Box 4)
    - Elton Glaser 1972-1996, 71 items (3 folders) (Box 4)
    - Louise Gluck (1943-) 1971-1993, 6 items (Box 4)
    - Arnie & Betty Goldstein 1985-1998, 13 items (Box 4)
    - Jorie Graham (1951-) 1978-1993, 13 items (Box 4)
    - Loren Graham (1958-) 1994-1995, 7 items (Box 4)
    - Frank Graziano (1955-) 1978-1983, 17 items (Box 5)
    - Ha 1971-1997 (Box 5)
      including: Rachel Hadas, Charles Hagenah, John Haines, Jim Hall, Daniel Halpern, Colin Hamilton, David Hamilton, Melissa Hammerle, Archie Hardy, James L. Harmon, William Harmon, Michael S. Harper, David Harris, Jeffrey Harrison, Henry Hart, Jim Hartz, William Hauser, John E. Hawkes, Tom Hawks
    - He-Hy 1973-1998 (Box 5)
      including: Anthony Hecht, David Heimer, Barbara Heizer, Jim Hejna, Gregory Hengesbaugh, Graham Hettlinger, George Hitchcock, Kells Hogan, Gill Holland, Henry Hollenberg, John Clellon Holmes, Charles Hood, Kathy R. Howard, Richard Howard, Cyrus Hoy, Robert A. Hueckstedt, Harry Humes, Stanley H. Hyman
    - Donald Hall (1928-) 1983-1988, 10 items (Box 5)
    - Oakley Hall 1967-1978, 14 items (Box 5)
    - Michael Hannon 1984-1994, 10 items (Box 5)
    - Kevin Hart (1954-) 1995-1998, 7 items (Box 5)
    - Peter Henry 1995-1997, 6 items (Box 5)
    - William Heyen (1940-) 1983-1996, 8 items (Box 5)
    - Tedd Higgs 1985-1990, 8 items (Box 5)
    - Brenda Hillman 1975-1994, 37 items (Box 5)
    - Edward Hirsch 1985-1992, 7 items (Box 5)
    - Garrett Hongo (1951-) 1978-1996, 22 items (Box 5)
    - I 1984-1994 (Box 6)
      including: Priscilla Ineff, Earl Ingersoll, Mark Irwin
    - J 1978-1996 (Box 6)
      including: Robert H. Jacob, Leland S. Jamieson, Rod Jellema, Elizabeth Jenkins, Jonathan Johnson, Judy Jordan, Lawrence Joseph, Don Junkins
    - Mark Jarman (1952-) 1975-1997, 44 items (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Donald Justice (1925-) 1969-1990, 142 items (5 folders) (Box 6)
    - Correspondence K 1973-1997 (Box 7)
      including: Justin Kaplan, Judy Karasik, Deborah Keenan, John Keene, Hunter Kennedy, Joe Kennedy, Jennifer Key, Thomas N. & Carol B. Key, Kerry Shawn Keys, Mary Kinzie, Karl Kirchwey, Melissa Kirsch, Janet Knepper, Joseph Knittle, Damon, Sharon Kubasak, Maxine Kumin, John W. Kuykendall
    - Edmund Keeley (Mike) 1974-1997, 11 items (Box 7)
    - James Kimbrell (1967-) 1994-1998, 8 items (Box 7)
    - Doug King 1986-1997, 5 items (Box 7)
    - Galway Kinnell (1927-) 1971 & 1980, 3 items (Box 7)
    - Susan Kinsolving 1986-1990, 10 items (Box 7)
    - Yusef Komunyakaa (1947-) 1987, 1 item (Box 7)
    - La-Le 1970-1997 (Box 7)
      including: Andy Lakritz, Linda Lappin, Philip Larkin, Carolyn Lau, Steve Lautermilck, Sydney Lea, Kristy Lee, Rolf Leeman, Margitt Lehbert, Daniel G. Leidig, Graham Leonard, Larry Levis
    - Li-Lu 1984-1998 (Box 7)
      including: Carl Little, Robert Hill Long, James Longenbach, Robert Longoni, Jon Loomis, John Lord, James Lott, Emily Lu
    - John Lang 1991-1998, 11 items (Box 7)
    - Deborah Larsen 1984-1994, 24 items (Box 7)
    - James Laughlin (1914-) 1996, 5 items (Box 7)
    - David Lehman (1948-) 1984-1995, 7 items (Box 7)
    - Phil Levine (1928-) 1968-1997, 207 items (9 folders) (Box 8)
    - Tom Lux (1946-) 1970-1980, 19 items (Box 9)
    - Mc 1975-1997 (Box 9)
      including: Elizabeth McBride, Davis McCombs, James McCorkle, David W. McCullough, Cynthia McDonald, Marty McGovern, Rex McGuinn, Michael McGuire, John McIntire, Louis McKee, Virginia McKee, Anne McKeithen, John McKernan, Leigh McLellan, Sandy McPherson
    - J.D. McClatchy "Sandy" (1945-) 1975-1996, 46 items (Box 9)
    - Michael McFee 1985-1991, 6 items (Box 9)
    - Lynne McMahon 1983-1997, 12 items (Box 9)
    - James McMichael 1970-1984, 31 items (Box 9)
    - Ma-Mi 1976-1997 (Box 9)
      including: Mark Madigan, M. Maggi, John Malcolm, Irving Malin, Marianna Manclossi, Coretta Marshall, Mike Martin, William Maxwell, Loredana May, Sue Ann Mead, William Meredith, Kim Merker, Anne Michaels, C. Wolfram Swetz von Middhlar, Jane Miller, Joseph C. Miller, Judy K. Miller, Michael Miller, Amy Minett, Ana Mitric
    - Mo-Mu 1984-1997 (Box 9)
      including: Paul Monette, Lorne Mook, Hugh Moorhead,Pedro Escudero Moreno, Berry Morgan, Elizabeth Morgan, John Morgan, Vance Morgan, Edward Morin, Albert F. Moritz, Mary Morris, John H. Morrison, Craig Mueller, Jenny Mueller, Maureen Mulhern, Rick Mulkey, Michael Murphy
    - Gerald Malanga (1943-) 1971-1996, 9 items (Box 9)
    - Jackie Marcus 1988-1990, 9 items (Box 9)
    - Lynn Martin 1984-1988, 14 items (Box 10)
    - William Matthews (1942-) 1972-1995, 9 items (Box 10)
    - Bill Merwin (1927-) 1975-1981, 11 items (Box 10)
    - Robert Mezey (1935-) 1969-1989, 6 items (Box 10)
    - Lenny Michaels (1933-) 1976-1984, 6 items (Box 10)
    - Susan Mitchell (1944-) 1984-1989, 5 items (Box 10)
    - Robert Morgan (1944-) 1984-1998, 45 items (Box 10)
    - Howard Moss (1922-1987) 1979-1986, 16 items (Box 10)
    - Lisel Mueller (1924-) 1982, 1 item (Box 10)
    - Carol Muske-Dukes (1945-) 1976-1996, 27 items (Box 10)
    - N 1984-1997 (Box 11)
      including: Shelly Nameroff, Peter Nijmeijer, Heidi Lynn Nilsson, Denis Noel, Howard Norman
    - O 1978-1994 (Box 11)
      including: Joyce Carol Oates, Robert J. Oberg, Daniel S. Ogbe, Steve Orlen, Greg Orr, Linda Orr, Antonio Lopez Ortega, Victor Ourin
    - Ingrid O'Brien 1974, 6 items (Box 11)
    - Pa-Pi 1972-1998 (Box 11)
      including: Ron Padgett, Michael Palmer, Suzanne Paola, Greg Pape, Jay Parini, Joseph Parisi, Charlie Parish, Kelli R. Patton, Frank H. Pearl, Lu Peck, Michael Peich, Heather Pendergraft, Sam Pereira, Marjorie Perloff, William Phillips, Marge Piercy, L. Piller, Robert Pinsky, Giancarlo Piscione
    - Pl-Pz 1984-1998 (Box 11)
      including: Don Platt, Russell Platt, Marise A. Pokorny, Luke Ives Pontifell, Al Poulin, Jr., Gaetano Prampolini, Clifford W. Price, Bill Pritchard, Wyatt Prunty
    - Eric Pankey (1959-) 1995-1997, 18 items (Box 11)
    - Stan Plumly (1939-) 1975-1995, 19 items (Box 11)
    - Q 1988-1994 (Box 11)
      including: Isa de Quesada, Alice Quinn, Ricardo J. Quinones
    - Ra-Ri 1974-1997 (Box 11)
      including: Larry Raab, Jim Randall, Robert Randolph, Random House, Inc., Bob Rees, Richard Reeve, Melanie Rehak, James Reiss, David Remnick, Paige Rense, Jan Richman, John Ridland, Dan Rifenburgh, Mrs. J.W. Richel
    - Ro-Ry 1972-1997 (Box 11)
      including: Eunice Robeck, Ellen Roberson, Janet Roberts, the Rockefeller Foundation, Joseph Rodrigues, Jr., William Pitt Root, Paul B. Roth, Louis D. Rubin, Jr., William Ruddy, Mark Rudman, A. Ellison Rumsey, Lex Runciman, Eleanor Rutledge, Peter Russell, Michael Ryan
    - Robert Caudle Rogers 1987-1998, 6 items (Box 11)
    - Maggie Ross 1986-1994, 14 items (Box 12)
    - Sa-Si 1973-1997 (Box 12)
      including: Patrick Samway, Stephen Sandy, Sarabande Books, Molly Schen, Grace Schulman, Robert Schultz, D.J. Schwichow, Nathan A. Scott, Jr., Jim Seay, Joseph Secondi, David W. Sedgwick, Julianne Seeman, Barry Seiler, Mary Serpico-Lay, Bill Sheppard, Rosa Shand, Rukmini M. Sichitiu, Christine A. Sikorski, Alex Silberman, Gary Silva, Merle Singer, P. Singh
    - Sk-Sp 1979-1997 (Box 12)
      including: David A. Skeel, Jr., Jeffrey Skinner, Tom Sleigh, Arthur Smith, Dean Smith, Gibbs M. Smith, Random Smith, Todd Smith, Ellison A. Smyth, Ross J. Smyth, Ann Snodgrass, Ted Solotaroff, Gary Soto, Marcia Southwick, Patricia Meyer Spacks, Amy Spanel
    - St-Sw 1972-1997 (Box 12)
      including: Bill Stafford, George Starbuck, George M. Steele, Rene Steinke, Lisa Stending, Gerald Stern, Amy Stewart, Gale Stewart, Jody Stewart, Stride Publications, Dabney Stuart, Adrienne Su, Ron Sukenick, David Summers, Dorothy Sutton, Mary Swander, Joan T. Swenson, Tree Swenson, David Swerdlow
    - Ira Sadoff (1945-) 1974-1981, 8 items (Box 12)
    - Mary Ann Samyn (1970-) 1995-1997, 9 items (Box 12)
    - Sherrod Santos (1948-) 1979-1994, 23 items (Box 12)
    - David St. John (1949-) 1975-1992, n.d., 67 items (3 folders) (Box 12-13)
    - Harold Schimmel 1972-1997, 31 items (Box 13)
    - Charles Seluzicki 1979-1992, 43 items (Box 13)
    - Charles Simic (1938-) [1970]-1996, 31 items (Box 13)
    - Maurya Simon 1983-1997, 28 items (Box 13)
    - Dave Smith (1942-) 1972-1994, 27 items (Box 13)
    - Marcia D. Smith, "Marky" 1984-1996, 54 items (3 folders) (Box 14)
    - Willard Spiegelman 1991-1995, 6 items (Box 14)
    - Peter Stitt 1983-1995, 21 items (Box 14)
    - Mark Strand (1934-) 1968-1994, n.d., 37 items (2 folders) (Box 14)
    - Larissa Szporluk 1994-1995, 6 items (Box 14)
    - Mary Szybist 1994-1997, 10 items (Box 14)
    - T 1983-1998 (Box 15)
      including: John Tagliabue, Indrek Tart, Phillip Taylor, Ross Taylor, Mac Test, Libby Thayer, Mike Theune, Stephen Thomas, Frances Thronson, Ann Townsend, Danielle Truscott
    - James Tate 1967-1990, n.d., 27 items (Box 15)
    - Alexander Thorburn 1984-1995, 16 items (Box 15)
    - Richard Tillinghast (1940-) 1979-1991, 6 items (Box 15)
    - Chase Twichell 1976-1993, 26 items (Box 15)
    - U 1987-1996 (Box 15)
      including: University of Michigan Press, University of Tennessee Lupton Library
    - Unidentified 1969-1998, 39 items (Box 15)
    - V 1976-1997 (Box 15)
      including: Jean Valentine, Corinna Vallianatos, Nance Van Winckel, Greg Varner, Reetika Vazirani, Helen Vendler, Richard F. Venezia, Ellen Bryant Voigt, Hans Christian von Baeyer
    - Wa-We 1977-1997 (Box 15)
      including: David Walker, Rosanna Warren, Patricia Waters, Watershed Foundation, Julia Watson, Miles G. Watson, Richard J. Weekley, Bruce Weigl, Ken Weisner, Barry Weller, Ingrid Wendt
    - Wi-Wy 1972-1998 (Box 15)
      including: Allen Wier, Dara Wier, Ann Williams, John Willson, Joseph Wilmott, Robert A. Wilson, Sam Witt, Tibor Wlassics, C.D. Wright, Barbara Wuest, Edith Wylder
    - Sidney Wade 1983-1997, 9 items (Box 16)
    - Diane Wakoski (1937-) 1970-1982, 8 items (Box 16)
    - Robert Penn Warren (1905-1989) 1978 & 1981, 2 items (Box 16)
    - Wesleyan University Press 1983-1996, 37 items (Box 16)
    - Betsy Tice White 1983-1997, 24 items (Box 16)
    - Richard Wilbur (1921-) 1974 & 1977, 2 items (Box 16)
    - C.K. Williams (1936-) 1972-1992, 38 items (2 folders) (Box 16)
    - Franz Wright (1953-) 1977-1996, 16 items (Box 16)
    - Jay Wright (1935-) 1988-1997, 26 items (Box 16)
    - Stuart Wright (9 items) 1983-1986, n.d., 9 items (Box 17)
    - Wright Family & Related 1970-1997, 43 items (2 folders) (Box 17)
    - X-Z 1973-1998 (Box 17)
      including: Max Yeh, Al Young, Dale Young, Gary Young, John A. Yount, Chris Yu, Corda Zajac, Bill Zander, Mary Zeppa
    - David Young (1936-) 1975-1993, n.d., 63 items (3 folders) (Box 17)
    - Yiheng Zhao 1982-1983, 5 items (Box 17)
  - B: Chonological Correspondence 1970-1998, n.d. (Box 17-21)